<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on jotaro shigeyama</title>
    <link>https://jotaros.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on jotaro shigeyama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Jotaro Shigeyama</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jotaros.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Jotaro Shigeyama (born in 1993) is currently a Master&amp;rsquo;s student at Hasso Plattner Institute in University of Potsdam / Cyber Interface Lab, the University of Tokyo. He is also a Ph.D candidate in Hasso Plattner Institute in University of Potsdam, with Prof. Patrick Baudisch. He is a fellow student of Funai Fountation for Information Technology (starting from 2019-). He is studying computer science in the graduate school of The University of Tokyo, after finished Associate degree in mechanical and electrical engineering in Tokuyama college of technology and Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in mechano-informatics engineering in the University of Tokyo with Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications,Awards</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/home/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications / Journals (Peer Reviewed)
 Thijs Roumen, Jotaro Shigeyama, Julius Romeo Cosmo Rudolph, Felix Grzelka, and Patrick Baudisch: SpringFit: Joints and Mounts that Fabricate on Any Laser Cutter, In Proceedings of UIST&amp;rsquo;19, October, 2019, New Orleans, LA, US.
 Jotaro Shigeyama, Takeru Hashimoto, Shigeo Yoshida, Takuji Narumi, Tomohiro Tanikawa, and Michitaka Hirose: Transcalibur: A Weight Shifting Virtual Reality Controller for 2D Shape Rendering based on Computational Perception Model, In Proceedings of CHI2019, Glasgow, Scotland, UK.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>