<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jotaro shigeyama</title>
    <link>https://jotaros.github.io/tags/interaction/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on jotaro shigeyama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Jotaro Shigeyama</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://jotaros.github.io/tags/interaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Self avatar pseudo-haptics in Virtual Reality</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/pseudo-haptics-vr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/pseudo-haptics-vr/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We propose a system that presents a feeling of resistive force by modifying joint angles of user’s avatar, and an approach to reduce a feeling of discomfort evoked by a conflict between visual and proprioceptive sensations. Pseudo-haptic feedback enables us to provide haptic sensations by making discrepancy between the position of user’s body in the real world and avatar which represents a part of user’s body in an immersive virtual environment without using any complicated devices. However, a larger discrepancy between proprioceptive and visual sensations can cause a feeling of discomfort to a user, which leads to reduce the effectiveness of pseudo-haptic feedback. Also, modifying a displacement of a body part cannot maintain a consistency of whole body parts of a user and an avatar under an immersive virtual environment. To avoid these problems, we proposed a pseudo-haptic approach of modifying a joint angle of avatar. Our experiments showed that modifying multiple joint angles of an avatar’s arm can reduce a feeling of discomfort but still presents a certain intensity of resistive force, compared to changing only a single joint angle. In the demonstration we show some applications of our proposed system using pseudo-haptic feedback system in a conventional VR system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jotaro Shigeyama&lt;/strong&gt;, Nami Ogawa, Takuji Narumi, Tomohiro Tanikawa and Michitaka Hirose: Presenting resistive force by modifying joint angles of an avatar, VRSJ Jounal Vol.22, No.3, 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jotaro Shigeyama&lt;/strong&gt;, Nami Ogawa, Takuji Narumi, Tomohiro Tanikawa and Michitaka Hirose: Presenting a pseudo-haptic feedback in immersive VR environment by modifying avatar&amp;rsquo;s joint angle, IEEE World Haptics 2017, June 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swinging 3D Lamps</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/swinging-3d-lamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/swinging-3d-lamps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;under construction&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AgIC Workshop Collection installation design</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/workshop_collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/workshop_collection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Workshop Collection 10&amp;rdquo;, held in Tokyo was full of families and children to experience the latest technologies.
AgIC workshop has exhibited an installation to show what&amp;rsquo;s possible with its product: conductive ink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The installation is designed to be one of Japanese ethnic ornament &amp;ldquo;Kazaguruma&amp;rdquo;, a litte windmill. Japanese ethnic pattern &amp;ldquo;Wagara&amp;rdquo; is printed with conductive ink on each mill with chip LED mouted. Sensors on the board detects human passage, and mills rotate as if wind blew on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We showed that flexible circuit design can easily be built and designing product can be also be flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lighting Coaster:AgIC Workshop design</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/agic_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/agic_workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We organized a new program of workshop where we made lightning coaster, using Circuit Sticker from Chibitronics.
AgIC got a 2nd prize in Global Fab Award in the event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project CoPRO</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/copro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/copro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>