<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jotaro shigeyama</title>
    <link>https://jotaros.github.io/tags/uist/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on jotaro shigeyama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Jotaro Shigeyama</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://jotaros.github.io/tags/uist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>springFit: Joints and Mounts that Fabricate on Any Laser-Cutter</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/springfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/springfit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jotaros.github.io/img/springfit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pantograph&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joints are crucial to laser cutting as they allow making three-dimensional objects; mounts are crucial because they allow embedding technical components, such as motors. Unfortunately, mounts and joints tend to fail when trying to fabricate a model on a different laser cutter or from a different material. The reason for this lies in the way mounts and joints hold objects in place, which is by forcing them into slightly smaller openings. Such “press fit” mechanisms unfortunately are susceptible to the small changes in diameter that occur when switching to a machine that removes more or less material (“kerf”), as well as to changes in stiffness, as they occur when switching to a different material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We present a software tool called springFit that resolves this problem by replacing the problematic press fit-based mounts and joints with what we call cantileverbased mounts and joints. A cantilever spring is simply a long thin piece of material that pushes against the object to be held. Unlike press fits, cantilever springs are robust against variations in kerf and material; they can even handle very high variations, simply by using longer springs. SpringFit converts models in the form of 2D cutting plans by replacing all contained mounts, notch joints, finger joints, and t-joints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://hpi.de/baudisch/projects/springfit.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thijs Roumen, &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jotaro Shigeyama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, Julius Romeo Cosmo Rudolph, Felix Grzelka, and Patrick Baudisch: SpringFit: Joints and Mounts that Fabricate on Any Laser Cutter, In Proceedings of UIST&amp;rsquo;19, October, 2019, New Orleans, LA, US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DualPanto: A Haptic Device that Enables Blind Users to Continuously Interact with Virtual Worlds</title>
      <link>https://jotaros.github.io/project/dualpanto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jotaros.github.io/project/dualpanto/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jotaros.github.io/img/dualpanto.png&#34; alt=&#34;Pantograph&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We present a new haptic device that enables blind users to continuously track the absolute position of moving objects in spatial virtual environments, as is the case in sports or shooter games. Users interact with DualPanto by operating the me handle with one hand and by holding on to the it handle with the other hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each handle is connected to a pantograph haptic input/output device. The key feature is that the two handles are spatially registered with respect to each other. When guiding their avatar through a virtual world using the me handle, spatial registration enables users to track moving objects by having the device guide the output hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows blind players of a 1-on-1 soccer game to race for the ball or evade an opponent; it allows blind players of a shooter game to aim at an opponent and dodge shots. In our user study, blind participants reported very high enjoyment when using the device to play (6.&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://hpi.de/baudisch/projects/dualpanto.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oliver Schneider, &lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jotaro Shigeyama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, Robert Kovacs, Thijs Jan Roumen, Sebastian Marwecki, Nico Boeckhoff, Patrick Baudisch, DualPanto: A Haptic Device that Enables Blind Users to Continuously Interact with Virtual Worlds,
In Proceedings of UIST&amp;rsquo;18, October, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;TO APPEAR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>